skyscanner.com.au 2017-12-30

# Privacy policy

Skyscanner is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and we make it our highest priority to safeguard the confidentiality of any and all personal information you provide to us. 

This policy, together with our [Terms of Service](http://www.skyscanner.net/termsofservice.aspx) and [Cookie Policy](http://www.skyscanner.net/cookiepolicy.aspx), sets out the approach that we, [Skyscanner Limited](https://www.skyscanner.net/companydetails.aspx), take to the collection and handling of any such information and applies to all websites, mobile apps and other services operated by us such as newsletters and price alerts (the “Skyscanner Services”). 

By using the Skyscanner Services you are deemed to agree to our use of your information in accordance with this policy. We encourage you take a few minutes to read through and [contact us](https://help.skyscanner.net/) if you have any queries. 

In the event of any changes to our approach, we will update this policy and post the latest version on this page – please check back regularly to ensure you remain up to date.

**What kind of information does Skyscanner collect?**

Most information that we collect from you is linked to non-personal identifiers such as anonymous User IDs or device IDs, and does not enable you to be identified as an individual in the offline world (“Non-Personal Information”). Such Non-Personal Information includes things like your browser type, the type of device you are using, access times, the website you arrived at Skyscanner from, the features or functionality you selected whilst using the Skyscanner Services and your general geographic location. 

Where necessary, we will also collect information from you that does enable you to be identified as an individual in the offline world, such as your name, email address, passport number or payment details (“Personal Information”). In order to minimise the impact on your privacy, we will never knowingly collect more Personal Data than is strictly necessary to perform the activities described in this policy. 

**How and when does Skyscanner collect this information?**

We collect information that you voluntarily provide to us during your use of the Skyscanner Services. This can range from Non-Personal Information, such as the dates and desired destination you ask us to run a flight search against, to the Personal Information you are required to submit where you wish to book a flight with a travel supplier via the Skyscanner Services. Whether or not you provide us with this kind information is always entirely under your control.

In addition to information that you voluntarily provide to us, we also collect certain Non-Personal Information directly from you as you use the Skyscanner Services, as well as indirectly where it is provided to us automatically by the third party application, social networking site (such as Facebook or Twitter) or other website (such as a promotion partner) that you connect to the Skyscanner Services from.

**How does Skyscanner use this information?**

_To deliver the Skyscanner Services_

We use your information to deliver the Skyscanner Services and the specific features and functionality you request. This includes things like generating the search results that most accurately match your search criteria, storing your Personal Information to enable you to pre-fill future booking forms, facilitating the completion of any bookings with a third party supplier via the Skyscanner Services, assisting you with post-booking issues, or emailing you newsletters or price alerts that you have selected to receive. 

_To optimise & personalise the Skyscanner Services_

In addition to using your information to deliver the essential aspects of the Skyscanner Services, we also use it to optimise and personalise your experience of the Skyscanner Services. For example, we will use [cookies](https://www.skyscanner.net/cookiepolicy.aspx) to remember your language and currency preferences and may also personalise your experience by highlighting or recommending certain information or travel options that we believe is relevant to you based on your search history and use of the Skyscanner Services. 

_To deliver appropriate advertising_

We use Non-Personal Information, such as what you have searched for on the Skyscanner Services or your general geographic location, to present you with relevant advertisements. For example, we may use third party advertisement retargeting services to send you an advertisement related to destination you have searched for. We will never use your Personal Information to do this unless you explicitly authorise us. 

_To better understand, improve and protect the Skyscanner Services_

We use information we collect about how users interact with the Skyscanner Services in order to identify and correct faults, improve our services and inform business decisions, as well as for security and fraud-prevention purposes.

_To generate aggregated datasets that inform our business and the travel industry_

We use information we collect about users to generate datasets of Non-Personal Information. These datasets allow us to generate helpful product insights. For example, we can monitor demand for destinations to make sure the fares and the travel options our users want are available on the Skyscanner Services. 

_To contact you_

We use your information to contact you with confirmations, notifications or alerts you have requested, such as email newsletters or price alerts, or which are otherwise necessary for us to send to you in order to provide the Skyscanner Services you have selected, such as details of any bookings you have made on the Skyscanner platform. We may also notify you about any changes or updates to the Skyscanner Services or to this policy, our [Cookie Policy](https://www.skyscanner.net/cookiepolicy.aspx) or our [Terms of Service](https://www.skyscanner.net/termsofservice.aspx), or to respond to communications you have sent us, such as via our customer service [help centre](https://help.skyscanner.net/) or on social media.

**Do any third parties collect information about me when I use the Skyscanner Services?**

Yes, where you make a booking with a third party travel provider from within the Skyscanner platform, any information you submit as part of the booking process may be collected by that third party in order to process the booking. Your information will be used by those third parties in accordance with their own terms and conditions and privacy policy, a link to which will be provided to you during the booking process.

In addition, third party advertisement services may collect Non-Personal Information from you as you use the Skyscanner Services via cookies and other similar technologies. This information enables you to be served with relevant advertisements, both on the Skyscanner Services and on third party websites and applications around the web. Further information about the use of such technologies, and how to stop them, is set out in the _‘How does Skyscanner use cookies and other tracking technologies?’_ section below. 

**When will Skyscanner share your information with third parties?**

_Sharing Personal Information with third parties who process it only under Skyscanner’s instruction_

We share information relating to our users with selected third parties who perform services on our behalf and under our instruction (“Third Party Processors”). We ensure that any Third Party Processor which handles information on our behalf does so pursuant to contractual terms which require that the information is kept secure and, where that information contains any Personal Information, is processed in accordance with applicable data protection laws and used only as we have instructed and not for that Third Party Processor’s own purposes (unless you have explicitly consented to them doing so). 

Third Party Processors may be located in, or process your information, outside of the country in which you are based. Where our use of a Third Party Processor involves the transfer of Personal Data from within Europe to a location outside of the European Economic Area, we will put in place appropriate measures to ensure that the Personal Data is adequately protected in that location, most often by applying European Commission-approved [standard contractual clauses](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/transfer/index_en.htm) and robust security checks.

_Sharing information within the Skyscanner group_

Elements of the Skyscanner Services are supported by group companies that are wholly owned subsidiaries of ours (“Skyscanner Group Companies”). Accordingly, your information may from time to time be shared with such Skyscanner Group Companies for processing on our behalf. Where this happens, we ensure that detailed agreements are put in place that require such Skyscanner Group Companies to use it only in accordance with this policy and the purposes set out above. 

_Sharing your information with third parties for processing outside Skyscanner’s control_

We will share your Personal Information with third parties for processing outside Skyscanner’s control and for their own purposes in the following two scenarios: (1) where you make a booking with a third party travel provider from within the Skyscanner platform, any Personal Information you submit as part of the booking process will be shared with that third party in order to enable the booking to be processed; and (2) where you expressly authorise us to, such as where we run a promotion in conjunction with a partner and you instruct us to share your email address with that third party for the purpose of receiving promotional emails. 

If you are purchasing travel on the Skyscanner Services’ booking platform, we may share information (including Personal Information) with the travel provider for their standard verification and fraud-detection purposes, or to a third party contracted to provide those services on the travel provider’s behalf.

Non-Personal Information, such as fully anonymised datasets containing aggregated Skyscanner Services’ usage information or trend-level travel insights, may be shared by us with third parties. As described above, third party advertising businesses may collect Non-Personal Information from you via cookies and other tracking tools whilst using the Skyscanner Services.

_Disclosing information for legal and other reasons_

We may disclose your information where necessary to enforce our [Terms of Service](https://www.skyscanner.net/termsofservice.aspx) or other agreements, or to a prospective buyer or ultimate buyer if Skyscanner itself (or part of our business) is sold. We may also disclose your information if necessary to prevent, detect or prosecute illegal or suspected illegal activities or to prevent other damage or in response to a legal action against us or to enforce our rights and claims.

**How does Skyscanner keep my Personal Information safe and secure?**

We make the confidentiality and security of your Personal Information our highest priority and we limit access to it to only those Skyscanner employees who need to come into contact with it in order to fulfil their role and enable the Skyscanner Services to be provided to you. 

Although we do our best to protect your Personal Information, the transmission of information via the internet can never be completely secure and we are therefore unable to guarantee the security of the information which you share with us at your own risk. 

**Where does Skyscanner store my information?**

The information we collect from you is stored on secure servers in various locations around the world. However, any Personal Information we collect from you is only stored within servers located in either the UK, Ireland, or Singapore, or in the country from which you access the Skyscanner Services where required by law. Regardless of location, we ensure that adequate technical and organisational measures are in place to protect the security of any information we store on our servers. 

**Does Skyscanner use cookies or other tracking tools?**

We use a combination of cookies and similar tracking technologies (for example, on mobile devices we use non-persistent device ID techniques like IDFA and Android Advertising) to collect, in line with this policy, Non-Personal Information from you relating to how you are using the Skyscanner Services. Please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.skyscanner.net/cookiepolicy.aspx) for more detailed information on how the Skyscanner Services make use of these technologies. 

As explained above, third party advertisers will also collect Non-Personal Information from you using cookies and similar technologies for the purposes of serving you relevant adverts both on the Skyscanner Services and on other third party platforms as you move around the web, including on different devices. You may be able to control how these technologies are applied to you via the settings in your browser or on your mobile’s operating system. For more information and to know your choices, see the [Network Advertising Initiative website](http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/what-are-my-options/). 

**Do third party platforms comply with this policy?**

The Skyscanner Services contain links to third party websites and applications and may sometimes give you the option to export information to those platforms. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such third party websites. When you leave or otherwise cease using the Skyscanner Services, or transfer your information from the Skyscanner Services to a third party platform, we encourage you to read the applicable privacy policies of each and every third party platform that you allow to collect information from you.

**Does Skyscanner collect information from children?**

The Skyscanner Services are not intended for children under 13 years of age, and no one under the age of 13 may provide any information to, on or via the Skyscanner Services. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13, and will delete any that we learn we have collected or received that was not provided by, or with express consent on behalf of, the child’s parent or legal guardian. 

**How can I access or manage my Personal Information?**

If you have created an account with Skyscanner you can manage some of your Personal Information and subscription preferences from within your profile settings.

You also have the right to ask us not to process your Personal Information for marketing purposes at any time. You can exercise this right by [contacting us](http://www.skyscanner.net/contactus.aspx) at any time. You can also opt-out of receiving any non-essential emails, including marketing emails, by clicking the unsubscribe link contained at the bottom of such emails.

We are happy to provide you with details of the Personal Information we are holding about you at any point in time. Where you wish to make such a request, please submit it in writing, along with proof of your identity, to Skyscanner, Quartermile One, 15 Lauriston Place, Edinburgh EH3 9EN marked for the attention of ‘Chief Legal Officer’.

There are a number of useful tools and resources you can use to control your privacy online, for example via [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) or the [Network Advertising Initiative](https://www.networkadvertising.org/). We particularly recommend you get to know the privacy features and settings of the browser you use. 

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this policy, please [contact us here](https://help.skyscanner.net/), or by letter to Skyscanner, Quartermile One, 15 Lauriston Place, Edinburgh EH3 9EN marked for the attention of ‘Chief Legal Officer’.
